Bolanle AKINYEMI

Phone Number: 07464447500 Email: bola.akinyemi@hotmail.com

Summary

Junior Manual QA Tester: committed, hardworking and passionate tester delivering quality software for business and product owners. I am highly competent in analysing test requirements, finding effective test scenarios and identifying appropriate testing solutions to meet business requirements.

Operational risk Associate: excellent organisational skills, a high degree of attention to detail and a desire for getting to the root cause of an issue. Working with senior management to identify key risks and controls, evaluate inherent and residual risk, and establish mitigation plans. Strong understanding of operational risk and associated regulations.

Compliance officer: good understanding and able to advise on compliance issues with various relevant regulations. Identify potential risks and determine appropriate level of due diligence. First point of Contact for any communication or regulatory/contractual notifications received from Clients/Business partners/suppliers and ensure all relevant Stakeholders are informed in a timely manner

Business/Product Knowledge: over 5 years' experience across a range of financial, risk and compliance environments, working as an integral member of teams. Possesses exceptional interpersonal communication skills, liaising and negotiating competently with clients and stakeholders at all levels to provide expert advice and support as well as understanding TCF and KYC.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Love Circular

Trainee UX/UI Designer, (Nov. 21 to Feb 22)

- 13 weeks of intense project-based learning, teaching me the core concepts and fundamentals of design
- Developing a thorough understanding of UX/UI principles and common practices including research, ideation, design fundamentals, delivery & validation
- Creating daily conceptual designs and problem solving
- Presenting design projects weekly
- Collaborating with my team and love circular alumni to deliver designs
- Engaging in the design community through the sharing of resources and knowledge and providing feedback to others

London School of Informatics

Junior Manual QA Tester, (FEB. 21 to August 22)

The project involved system integration testing of the new online web application.

- Engaging with business to outline and document business requirements in form of use cases.
- Analyses Business and Functional requirements specification documents to identify test scenarios, test conditions, test data and test cases.
- Writing test level plans, test cases and test scripts.
- Wrote and executed UAT scripts for mandatory changes to "Ukflooringsale.co.uk"
- Quality center for test planning, execution, defect management, control and reporting.
- Raised test incidents and liaised with 3rd party developers on defect resolution.
- Executing UAT scripts alongside business representatives.
- Maintaining documentation relating to the defect tracking process within the project.
- Investigating test requirements and problems to identify appropriate testing solutions, which will meet requirements.
- Liaised with configuration team to ensure environments are updated and communicating with developer to ensure bugs and defects are corrected accordingly.
- Experience in using various test management tool such as Jira and ALM in creating requirement, writing test scripts, performing test executions, computing test matrixes, tracking defects and test reporting.
- Experience in testing software applications built on different operating systems such as Windows operating systems, Linux, UNIX and Mac OS.
- Experience of various types of testing including system testing, U.A.T, functional testing, database testing, smoke/sanity testing, integration testing, static testing, regression, dynamic testing and exploratory testing.

Deloitte Consulting

Operational Risk Associate (January 2020- Jan 2021)

- Risk associated with different business areas
- Monitor and manage the risk log to ensure it is up-to-date, relevant and reflective of the engagement's risk profile
- Performed risk identification, assessment, reporting and monitoring operations
- Identified project risks and dependencies and recommended corrective actions
- Supporting the incident management process in carrying out root cause analysis on any incidents identified, carrying out effective remediation and implementing effective control processes
- Promoting engagement on risk management across the organisation to ensure risk practices are well embedded in the organisations culture
- Developed monthly reports on project risks
- Utilising daily MI and analysing reports, spreadsheets and systems
- Ensuring all TLs complete their Risk & Control Assessment (RCSA) test correctly.

Remediation Analyst (October 2019 - January 2020)

- Improved risk and compliance management using Validate, Dow Jones systems to evaluate third party risks and provide solutions to ensure successful project completion
- Worked with management to develop risk mitigation strategies.

- Interpreting Financial Ombudsman guidelines to ensure policy limitation are clearly provided to the customer.
- Planning, implementing and overseeing risk-related programs
- Creating and coordinating proper reporting channels for compliance issues
- Coordinating and scheduling required compliance training for employees

Senior pension Administration (August 2018 - October 2019)

- Effectively managing individual caseloads utilising strong administration and prioritisation
- Identifying data subject right requests in line with the *General Data Protection Regulation* (GDPR) and resolving Customer needs on a first call resolution basis.
- Determining if compensation for financial loss and/or a distress and inconvenience payment is appropriate and at what level.
- First point of contact for all clients' queries, client on boarding and client administration
- Processing and authorising all types of pension claims as well as managing pension transfers
- Liaising with technical specialists and relevant departments such as compliance to gain sign off on any new processes ensuring compliance with current regulation
- Ownership of more complex cases and escalating any issues that may impact SLA to Senior Management

Globe Business Media Group

Event Assistant / Risk assistant (May 2018 - August)

- Adhering to direct marketing regulations as required in the (GDPR) and the Privacy & Electronic Communications Regulation, in all marketing electronic communications.
- Complying with the Advertising Standards Authority; CAP code in all direct marketing materials.
- Conducting pre and post event reports and evaluations with team members, reporting outcomes to senior leads including reporting of event budget and spend.

Guide Dogs for the Blind Association

Individual Campaign Executive (March 2017-May 2018)

- Responding to direct marketing opt-outs and erasure requests, ensuring requests are noted and individuals are included to suppression mailing lists.
- Keeping abreast of any proposed changes by the Fundraising Regulator, as well as complying
 with all direct marketing, data protection regulations and code of practices for all marketing
 activities.
- Managing the day-to-day delivery of the campaign requirements, to time budget making and implementing recommendations for improvement
- Completed and updated Best Practice and Operations manuals as required.
- Managed and maintained the charity certifications.
- Contributed to the implementation and continuous improvement of processes and policies across the business including identifying opportunities to increase profitability compliantly.
- Conducted internal audits across all areas of the business to monitor compliance.
- Maintained an effective and accurate record of training in compliance with Guide Dogs for the Blind Association training system policy and procedure.
- Worked closely with the rest of the Compliance Team

WSH-Baxerstorey

Senior Supply Chain Administrator (Jan 2017-March 2017)

- Managing the setup of new business by setting up accounts with suppliers and ensuring all orders are placed and delivered in time for the 'go live' date requested.
- Ownership of more complex cases and escalating any issues that may impact SLA to Senior Management
- First point of contact for all clients' queries, client on boarding and client administration
- Ensuring all documents relating to supply chain providers are retained in compliance with the company's quality requirements.
- Offering front line support via email/phone to current and new customers regarding supply of goods.

KEY SKILLS

- Good knowledge of risk analysis
- Ability to process detailed information quickly, effectively and consistently
- Good judgmental skills in identifying risk and priorities.
- Rapid test case creator
- Excellent Team player
- Ability to work in constantly changing fast paced environment.
- Flexible and able to learn and adapt to new technologies quickly.
- Strong problem-solving skills, demonstrating a logical and analytical approach
- Can perform under pressure and demonstrate strong project management skills by following to tight deadlines and stringent controls
- Absorbs new information readily and is able to put it into practice effectively
- Good time management skills and able to prioritise work effectively
- Proven ability to be a team player, while retaining the ability to work independently using my own initiative
- Proficient in Excel and experienced in using web-based software tools

Risk Management | Compliance | Project & Case Management | Stakeholder management | Customer Engagement | Data Analysis | KYC | AML | Compliance management

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

September 2013 -2016

Events Management (BA)University of Northampton

HOBBIES

• I enjoy reading novels or any other piece of literature, trying out new recipes and travelling.